<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ravi-Hara</title><link>https://www.ravihara.in/en/</link><description>Recent content on Ravi-Hara</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2021-2022 Ravishankar Haranath. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 09:30:24 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ravihara.in/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Earthly CI-CD with Podman</title><link>https://www.ravihara.in/en/posts/earthly-podman-setup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 09:30:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.ravihara.in/en/posts/earthly-podman-setup/</guid><description>The Earthly is an effortless CI/CD framework that combines the power of Docker, Makefile and Bash and provides an easy to use build system that runs locally and on cloud based systems such as Github-Actions, Circle-CI and so on.
Earthly will look for docker eventhough it doesn&amp;rsquo;t depend on it explicitly. For those who prefer podman as an alternate to using docker the following guide will help in setting up Earthly to use podman instead of docker.</description></item><item><title>Earthly for Debian based systems</title><link>https://www.ravihara.in/en/posts/setup-apt-earthly/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 08:30:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.ravihara.in/en/posts/setup-apt-earthly/</guid><description>Here is a link to the bash-script to configure apt repository for Earthly . The script is available as a GitHub Gist. Hence, you are requested to open the link to the bash-script and download the script (or, copy-paste the raw content into a file using a text-editor) to use it directly from your Debian-based system such as Debian, Ubuntu or LinuxMint (including LMDE).
The script will setup the proper apt repository configuration file under /etc/apt/sources.</description></item><item><title>Podman for Debian based systems</title><link>https://www.ravihara.in/en/posts/setup-apt-podman/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 08:30:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.ravihara.in/en/posts/setup-apt-podman/</guid><description>Here is a link to the bash-script to configure apt repository for Podman . The script is available as a GitHub Gist. Hence, you are requested to open the link to the bash-script and download the script (or, copy-paste the raw content into a file using a text-editor) to use it directly from your Debian-based system such as Debian, Ubuntu or LinuxMint (including LMDE).
The script will setup the proper apt repository configuration file under /etc/apt/sources.</description></item><item><title>Get next Github project version</title><link>https://www.ravihara.in/en/posts/git-project-next-version/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 13:55:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.ravihara.in/en/posts/git-project-next-version/</guid><description>Here is a script to find out the next suggested SemVer versions for a Github project. The script works on both private and public repositories. If using a private repo, you need to export an environment variable named GITHUB_PAT with the value of your github personal access token. This script depends mainly on the git tags. If you use a custom prefix for your git tags, you need to provide it as an option.</description></item><item><title>Using abstract class and interface in Java</title><link>https://www.ravihara.in/en/posts/java-class-vs-iface/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 11:55:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.ravihara.in/en/posts/java-class-vs-iface/</guid><description>This post captures various best-practices and/or useful suggestions which might come handy while programming in Java. These are purely my observations and opinion using Java as the programming language to create backend services and cross-platform applications. Moreover, I have been using the latest stable version of Java (v17 LTS). Hence, some of the points might not be relevant to older versions. But, I try to capture the features which are common enough in the recent past.</description></item><item><title>Mount Google-Drive in Ubuntu</title><link>https://www.ravihara.in/en/posts/gdrive-fuse-mount/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 13:55:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.ravihara.in/en/posts/gdrive-fuse-mount/</guid><description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll be describing how to setup automatic mounting of one or more Google Drives locally, on your Ubuntu system. Following steps should generally work for the supported Ubuntu versions of the google-drive-ocamlfuse tool. Let&amp;rsquo;s just right into the setup steps.
Assumptions Here are the list of assumptions made for descriptive purposes. Please replace them with appropriate values based on your system and environment.
Normal user: ubuntu Base path for GDrive mount folders: $HOME/Store (Ex.</description></item><item><title>Home Wifi with CDMA modem</title><link>https://www.ravihara.in/en/posts/usb-cdma-wifi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 11:36:50 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.ravihara.in/en/posts/usb-cdma-wifi/</guid><description>In case CDMA technology is still offered in your area, this post might be useful to you in setting up a simple Home WiFi using a CDMA modem, WiFi router and a Linux machine. This could be a good excercise to revive your old Linux box and that old WiFi router which had been laying useless :-).
What you need Linux machine - An old Debian / Ubuntu Linux pc will do too.</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://www.ravihara.in/en/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ravihara.in/en/about/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a software programmer and architect by profession, promoting free and open source software (FOSS) based solutions to businesses. Traveling, World Culture, Traditions, Literature and Music interests me. I speak primarily in Kannada, a beautiful language of South Indian state of Karnataka and one of the classical languages of India.
Thanks for visiting.</description></item><item><title>Contact Me</title><link>https://www.ravihara.in/en/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ravihara.in/en/contact/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>